# Lei Wang

I am a hardworking, passionate, and self-disciplined researcher.



Lei Wang holds the position of Research Fellow at ANU and serves as a Visiting Scientist at Data61/CSIRO. Additionally, he works as a Computer Scientist at Active Intelligence Australia Pty Ltd. Since 2018, he has been employed as a Computer Vision Researcher at iCetana Pty Ltd. In the past, he held roles as a Visiting Researcher at Data61/CSIRO and at UWA.

**Research Interests:** action recognition in videos | anomaly detection | video image processing | one- and few-shot learning | deep learning | tensor learning | domain adaptation

#### Education

Doctor of Philosophy (PhD), Computer Science, The Australian National University (ANU)	2019/07-2023/02
Master of Professional Engineering, Software Engineering, The University of Western Australia (UWA)	2016/02-2018/03

## **Experience**

Research Fellow (Level B)   ANU College of Engineering, Computing and Cybernetics	2023/02-present
Visiting Researcher, Postgraduate research student, Visiting Scientist   CSIRO's Data61, Australia	2018/09-present
Computer Scientist   Active Intelligence Australia Pty Ltd, Perth, Australia	2021/07-present
Machine Learning Researcher   Ebenezer Technologies, Barranquilla, Colombia	2020/09-2021/01
Visiting Researcher   Department of Comput. Sci. and Softw. Eng., UWA, Perth, Australia	2018/10-2019/10
Computer Vision Research Intern, Computer Vision Researcher   iCetana Pty Ltd, Perth, Australia	2018/07-2020/09

# Research Projects & Grants

- **Chief Investigator (CI)**, "Towards building general-purpose multimodal foundation models", NCI Adaptater Scheme Q4 2023 (**HPC funding scheme**), 2023/10/01-2023/12/31
- **Grant / Project Award** (Oracle Cloud credits award), "Automatic, large-scale screening of failure cases in autonomous driving", **A\$ 48,000**, 2023/07/26-2024/07/25
- Co-Investigator (Co-I), "Sharing early insights for more resilient communities", A\$ 71,089, 2023/04/06-2023/10/31
- Industry innovation (Active Intelligence Corp.), "Anomaly detection in surveillance videos", A\$ 123,368, 2021/07/01-2022/06/30

## **Teaching**

Teaching Assistant | Department of Comput. Sci. and Softw. Eng., UWA

2018/03-2018/07

- CITS5508 Machine Learning
- Unit Coordinator(s): A/Prof. Du Huynh & Prof. Mark Reynolds

# **Recognition & Honors**

- The Sang Uk Lee Best Student Paper Award, ACCV 2022, 2022/12/08
- The Incentive Unit Award, Active Intelligence Corp., 2022/09/09-2032/09/08
- Outstanding reviewer, ECCV 2022, 2022/10/19
- **Data61 Top-up Scholarship**, Data61/CSIRO, 2019/07/01-2023/06/30
- Data61 PhD Scholarship, Data61/CSIRO, 2019/07/01-2023/06/30
- ANU HDR Fee Remission Merit Scholarship, ANU, 2019/07/01-2023/06/30
- Outstanding Graduate Award, Yangzhou University, 2015/06
- Jingwen Zhu Scholarship, Yangzhou University, 2015/03
- Principal's Scholarship (First Class), Yangzhou University, 2014/12
- The Second Prize of Lanqiao Cup Competition (C/C++ Program Design), National Software and Information Technology Professional Talent Competition, 2014/04
- Principal's Scholarship (Second Class), Yangzhou University, 2013/12

## **Professional Service**

- I have the honor of serving as an **Area Chair** for the 27th International Conference on Pattern Recognition (ICPR 2024) by invitation from Prof. Cheng-Lin Liu (CASIA).
- I regularly review technical papers for the following journals, conferences & workshops.
  - Journals: TPAMI, TCSVT, TMM, PR, CVIU, NCAA, JVCI, SIVP, TVCJ, IET Computer Vision, Electronics Letters
  - Conferences: ICLR 2023-2024, AAAI 2022-2024, NeurIPS 2022-2023, ICML 2022-2023, CVPR 2022-2023, ICCV 2023, ECCV 2022, WACV 2024, BMVC 2020-2023, IEEE CAI 2023
  - Workshops: The AI City Challenge Workshop (CVPR 2023), Vision Datasets Understanding (CVPR 2022-2023), Deep Vision Workshop (CVPR 2020)

#### **Invited Talk**

- "The next generation of international Chinese young students face to face" Issue 21, International Cooperation and Exchange Program Series Activities of Harbin Institute of Technology (Shenzhen), 2023/08/12
  - Topic: Action Recognition: Past, Present and Future
  - Host: Prof. Haijun Zhang, Department of Computer Science, Harbin Institute of Technology, Shenzhen

#### **Publications**

- Conference/journal papers
  - **Lei Wang** and Piotr Koniusz. "3Mformer: Multi-order Multi-mode Transformer for Skeletal Action Recognition." *Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition*. 2023. A\*
  - **Lei Wang** and Piotr Koniusz. "Uncertainty-DTW for Time Series and Sequences." *European Conference on Computer Vision.* Cham: Springer Nature Switzerland, 2022. A\*, oral
  - Lei Wang and Piotr Koniusz. "Temporal-Viewpoint Transportation Plan for Skeletal Few-shot Action Recognition." Proceedings of the Asian Conference on Computer Vision. 2022. B, oral, Best Student Paper Award
  - Zhenyue Qin, Yang Liu, Pan Ji, Dongwoo Kim, Lei Wang, R.I. (Bob) McKay, Saeed Anwar, and Tom Gedeon. "Fusing Higher-Order Features in Graph Neural Networks for Skeleton-Based Action Recognition." *IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems* (2022). IF: 14.255
  - Lei Wang and Piotr Koniusz. "Self-supervising Action Recognition by Statistical Moment and Subspace Descriptors." Proceedings of the 29th ACM international conference on multimedia. 2021. A\*
  - Piotr Koniusz, **Lei Wang**, and Anoop Cherian. "Tensor Representations for Action Recognition." *IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence* 44.2 (2021): 648-665. **IF**: 24.314
  - Lei Wang, Piotr Koniusz, and Du Q. Huynh. "Hallucinating IDT Descriptors and I3D Optical Flow Features for Action Recognition with CNNs." 2019 IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision, IEEE Computer Society, 2019. A\*
  - **Lei Wang**, Du Q. Huynh, and Piotr Koniusz. "A Comparative Review of Recent Kinect-based Action Recognition Algorithms." *IEEE Transactions on Image Processing*, 29 (2019): 15-28. IF: 11.041
  - **Lei Wang**, Du Q. Huynh, and Moussa Reda Mansour. "Loss Switching Fusion with Similarity Search for Video Classification." 2019 IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP), IEEE, 2019. B, 1 AU patent
- Patents
  - Lei Wang. "System and Method of Detecting Anomalies from Mass Data." (US provisional, SN 63/326,525)
  - Lei Wang and Graeme Woods. "Method and System for Classifying Video Data." (au 2019903775, provisional patent filed 07/10/2019)
  - Lei Wang, Moussa Reda Mansour, and Graeme Woods. "System and Method of Video Data Retrieval." (au 2019900316, provisional patent filed 01/02/2019)
- Theses
  - **Lei Wang**. "Robust Human Action Modelling." *Ph.D. dissertation*, The Australian National University, Canberra, ACT, Australia, Oct. 2023.
  - **Lei Wang.** "Analysis and evaluation of Kinect-based action recognition algorithms." *M.S. thesis*, School Comput. Sci. Softw. Eng., Univ. Western Australia, Perth, WA, Australia, Nov. 2017.
- arXiv preprints
  - Lei Wang, Piotr Koniusz, Tom Gedeon, and Liang Zheng. "Adaptive Multi-head Contrastive Learning." arXiv, 2023.
  - Lei Wang and Piotr Koniusz. "Flow Dynamics Correction for Action Recognition." arXiv, 2023.
  - **Lei Wang**, Jun Liu, and Piotr Koniusz. "3D Skeleton-based Few-shot Action Recognition with JEANIE is not so Naïve." *arXiv*, 2021, an extended version has been accepted by ACCV'22 [oral].
  - **Lei Wang**, Piotr Koniusz, and Ke Sun. "High-order Tensor Pooling with Attention for Action Recognition." *arXiv*, 2021, an extension of our TPAMI'20.
  - Lei Wang. "Al in Software Engineering: Case Studies and Prospects." arXiv, 2017, technical report.